A Finding Aid to the Peter Blume Papers, 1870-2001, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Peter Blume papers
1870-2001
Archives of American Art
Blume, Peter, 1906-1992
AAA.blumpete
Archival Resource Key
7.6 Linear feet
The papers of New York and Connecticut painter Peter Blume date from 1870 to 2001 and measure 7.6 linear feet. Found are biographical materials; correspondence with family, friends, colleagues, galleries and institutions, and writers; writings on art by Blume and others; subject files regarding organizations, works of art, exhibitions, and reference files; personal business records; printed material; two scrapbooks; photographs of Blume, family, friends, and works of art; extensive artwork; and material relating to Blume's wife's family, the Cratons.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 10 series.
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, circa 1950-1992 (0.2 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1926-1992 (1.8 linear feet; Box 1-3)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, 1929-1986 (0.5 linear feet; Box 3, 9)
Series 4: Subject Files, circa 1930-1988 (0.5 linear feet; Box 3-4)
Series 5: Personal Business and Financial Records, 1934-1983 (0.6 linear feet; Box 4, 9)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1930-1990 (0.7 linear feet; Box 4-5, 9, OV 15-16)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1934-1944 (3 folders; Box 5)
Series 8: Photographs, 1917-circa 1980 (1.1 linear feet; Box 5-6, 9)
Series 9: Artwork, 1932-1984 (2.0 linear feet; Box 6-9, OV 10-14)
Series 10: Craton Family Papers, 1870-2001 (0.2 linear feet; Box 6)
Biographical / Historical
Russian-born painter and sculptor Peter Blume (1906-1992) was active in New York and Connecticut. His style combined American and European traditions with folk art and surrealism.
Peter Blume was born Piotr Sorek-Sabel in 1906 in Smorgon, Russia. With his family, he emigrated to the United States in 1911 and settled in New York City. Blume studied at the Educational Alliance and the Art Students League in New York. Influenced by folk art, Precisionism, Cubism, and Surrealism, Blume combined European and American painting tradition to create his own style. He was awarded a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1932 and travelled to Italy.
In 1934, Blume's South of Scranton (1931) won the first prize at the Carnegie International Exhibition. Later, he exhibited The Eternal City (1937) at the Julian Levy Galleries in Manhattan. With the Section of Painting and Sculpture of the Treasury Department, Blume completed two post office murals in New York and Pennsylvania. Blume was a member of the National Academy of Design and was active with the American Academy in Rome.
Peter Blume married Grace "Ebie" Douglas Craton in 1931. The couple built their home in Sherman, Connecticut. The Blumes travelled the world and kept close relationships with family and friends, such as Ann and Heber Blankenhorn, Malcolm Cowley, and Ned and Nancy Holsten.
Peter Blume died in Connecticut in 1992.
Scope and Contents
The papers of New York and Connecticut painter Peter Blume date from 1870 to 2001 and measure 7.6 linear feet. Found are biographical materials; correspondence with family, friends, colleagues, galleries and institutions, and writers; writings on art by Blume and others; subject files regarding organizations, works of art, exhibitions, and reference files; personal business records; printed material; two scrapbooks; photographs of Blume, family, friends, and works of art; extensive artwork; and material relating to Blume's wife's family, the Cratons.
Biographical materials include an award, obituaries, a travel itinerary, and sound recordings and transcripts of interviews of Peter Blume by Alfred H. Barr, Boston College, Harry Boursa, and Visionary Company Magazine.
Correspondence is professional and personal. Letters are from friends, family, artists, writers, galleries, and institutions. Notable correspondents include Kirk Askew, Malcolm Cowley, Peter DeVries, Joseph Hirsch, and Frank A. Trapp, among others. Also found is Grace Blume's correspondence which includes letters to and from Peter Blume and letters from Grace to her family members and friends. The bulk of Grace Blume's correspondence concerns her travels with Blume.
Writings and notes by Blume include a travel journal, lists of works of art, lectures, talks and other writings on art, artists, and friends. Writings by others include theses and scholarly papers about Blume, and include writings by Heber Blankenhorn, Kenneth Burke, Malcolm Cowley, Robert Ulrich Godsoe, Frank Getlein, Michael A. Kelly, and Frank A. Trapp. Also found is criticism on The Rock by school children.
Blume's subject files cover the American Academy of Arts and Letters, American Artists Congress, Heber Blankenhorn, works of art by Blume, exhibitions, and the Connecticut Council on the Arts. Also found are reference files consisting of photographs of artwork by others and clippings.
Personal business and financial records consist of business correspondence with galleries and museums; sales and consignment records; scattered price lists; and receipts and invoices relating to the building and running of Blume's house in Connecticut.
Printed materials include clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for solo and group shows, magazines featuring articles about Blume, posters, and reproductions of works of art.
Scrapbooks include a fragment of a scrapbook from 1942-1944 and a clippings scrapbook from 1934-1939.
Photographs include portraits and snapshots of Peter Blume, Grace Blume, family, friends, travel, parties, pets, homes, landscapes, exhibitions, and works of art. There are also photos of the Askews, the Blankenhorns, the Cowleys, Alfred Eisenstaedt, the Holstens, the Josephsons, Arthur Miller, Georgia O'Keeffe, the Sobys, and Raphael Soyer.
Artwork by Peter Blume includes completed drawings, sketches, doodles, prints, and preliminary drawings for many of his works. Of note are extensive sketches of heads, and preliminary drawings for Recollection of the Flood.
Craton family papers consist of geneological material relating to Grace Blume's brother, James Craton and his wife Catherine Sears Craton. Found are vital records; military records for James and Marshall Craton; correspondence; scattered financial records; clippings; and family photographs.
Related Materials
Also in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with Peter Blume conducted on August 16th, 1983 to May 23rd, 1984 by Robert F. Brown.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Peter Blume papers were donated by in 1993 by Grace Blume, Peter Blume's widow. Additional papers were donated by Catherine Weiss, Jamie Vance, and Leigh Butler in 2010.
Existence and Location of Copies
The collection was digitized in 2014 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Travel diaries; Sound recordings; Interviews; Drawings; Photographs; Prints; Transcriptions; Lectures; Scrapbooks; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Sketches; Askew, R. Kirk (Ralph Kirk), 1903-1974; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-; American Artists' Congress; De Vries, Peter, 1910-1993; Hirsch, Joseph, 1910-1981; Boston College; Boursa, Harry; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1902-1981; Trapp, Frank; Blume, Grace; Blankenhorn, Heber, 1884-1956; Burke, Kenneth, 1897-; Soyer, Raphael, 1899-1987; Connecticut Council of the Arts; Eisenstaedt, Alfred; Miller, Arthur, 1915-2005; Godsoe, Robert; Getlein, Frank; Kelly, Michael A.; American Academy of Arts and Letters
- Biographical Material, circa 1950-1992; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  Scattered biographical records include an award, Peter Blume's obituaries, a map of his birthplace Smorgon, a travel itinerary; and sound recordings and transcripts of interviews with Peter Blume by Alfred H. Barr, Boston College, Harry Bouras, and Visionary Company Magazine. Also found are genealogical records for Grace Blume's family, the Cratons. Researchers should note that the bulk of the Craton family papers are arranged in Series 10.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  This series has been partially scanned. Sound recordings have not been scanned.
  - Award, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Peter Blume, by Alfred H. Barr, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conversation with Peter Blume for Boston College, circa 1972; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Interview with Peter Blume by Harry Bouras, WFMT, 1976 January 11; 1976 January 18; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Interview with Peter Blume by Visionary Company Magazine, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Obituaries, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Also includes a map of Blume's birthplace
  - Travel Itinerary, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Grace Blume Biographical Material, circa 1950-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Craton Family genealogy
- Correspondence, 1926-1992; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.8 Linear feet Box 1-3
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  Professional and personal correspondence is with friends, family, artists, writers, galleries, museums, and institutions. Correspondents include Kirk Askew, Kenneth Burke, Malcolm Cowley, Charles Daniel, Peter and Katinka DeVries, John Hersey, Joseph Hirsch, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, and Frank A. Trapp, among many others. Some works of art have their own folder within correspondence as they reflect Blume's original order. All the letters are in reference to the specified artwork.
  Also found are letters written by Peter Blume to Grace Blume while Blume travelled or was working away from home. There are extensive letters written by Grace Blume to her sister and brother-in-law, Ann and Heber Blankenhorn and to friends, Nancy and Ned Holsten, mostly written during the Blume's travels abroad. Additional correspondence, particularly with galleries and museums, is found among the personal business and financial records. Also, scattered correspondence regarding genealogy is found in Series 10.
  - Albright Art Gallery, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Academy in Rome, 1956-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1947-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Associated Artists of Pittsburgh, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1938-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Art Students League, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Artists Welfare fund, Inc., 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Askew, Kirk and Constance, 1966-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - A, 1956-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Balicki, Mrs. Manan, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barr, Alfred H. Jr., circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Beal, Gifford, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bearden, Romare, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Becker, John, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bernard Davenberg Galleries, 1969-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Birmelin, Bob, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Blankenhorn, Heber and Ann, 1937-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    Includes some poetry by Heber Blankenhorn
  - Boyle, Kay, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Breitenbach, Thomas, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Brooks, Gladys Von Wyck, 1960-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Burke, Kenneth, 1943-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Caffin, Caroline, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Calder, Alexander and Louise, cirac 1960-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Campbell, William, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1934-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Cartwell, Bob, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Century Association, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Cheever, John, Mary, and Benjamin, 1962-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Coale, Joan, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Columbia University, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Columbus Museum of Art, 1934-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cone, Michelle N. C., 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Connecticut Commission on the Arts, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - CORE, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Cowles, Russell and Nancy, 1956-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1972-1974; 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48-49)
  - Crawford, Sidney Peak, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - C, 1956-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Daniels, Charles, 1926-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52-54)
  - DeVries, Peter and Katinka, 1974-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Diamond, David, 1968-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Dickinson, E.W., 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Diller, George E., 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Downtown Gallery, 1940-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Driscoll, John Paul, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Edel, Leon, 1975-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Editions Richelieu, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Evergood, Phillip, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - "Exhibitions", 1964-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Contains letters of praise from friends for exhibition openings
  - E, 1962-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Fellows, James, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Fogg Art Museum, 1932-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Ford Foundation, 1958-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Friend, David, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Gase, Dorothy, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Gilmore, Myron, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Goldfarb, Stephen, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Graziadei, Ercole, 1974-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Gross, Chaim and Renee, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1968-1980; 1936-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - G, 1965-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Hancock, Walker, 1971-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Hart Crane Newsletter, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Hersey, John, 1964-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Hellman, Lillian, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Hirsch, Joseph, 1951-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Hirshhorn, Joseph and Olga, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Holsten, Nancy and Ned, 1951-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Houston Museum of Fine Arts, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - H, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Imago Design Co., Inc., 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Ingersol, R. Sturgis, 1938-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Isaacs, Stanley, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Johnson, Donna, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Josephson, Hannah and Matthew, circa 1950-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 92-93)
  - Kantor, Sybil, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Karkadoulias Bronze Art, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Kaufmann, Edgar, 1938-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Kirshner, Leon, 1974-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Kirstein, George, Jane and Paulina, 1964-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Knoedler and Co., 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Kriss, Mark, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Lattimore, Richmond, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Life Magazine, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lighthill, Amy, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - LIndsey, Alexander, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1935-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - March, Florence and Frederic, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Markowitz, Gerald, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Martinu, Charlotte, 1958-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1942-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Midtown Galleries, 1934-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Modern Art Foundary, Inc., 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1959-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Motive Magazine, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Muller, Steve, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Municipal Art Committee, New York City, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - National Academy of Design, 1935-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - National Portrait Gallery, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Newhaus, Eugene, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - New Britain Museum of American Art, 1982-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - New York Times, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - New-Times, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Neward Museum, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Newberry Library, 1968-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Nordness Gallery, 1964-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Norman, Charles, 1969-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Oldbourne Book Company LTD, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Osborn, Bob, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Owing, Nat (?), 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Pach, Walter, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Pei, I.M. (and Partners), 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Piel, Mrs. Gerard, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Pinette, Carmen, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Porte (?), Katherine Anne, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Post Publishing Co., 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Powell, Dawn, 1962-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Pratt, George, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - P, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Randolph Macon Women's College, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Resor, Helen and Stanley, 1934-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Reynolds, Louise, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Robert Schoelkopf Gallery, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Roberts, L.P., 1970-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Robson, Peggy and Ernie, 1935-1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Rockefeller, Mrs. John D. (Abby), 1932-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Roe, Anne, 1944-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Rutgers, 1976-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - R, 1967-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Sachs, Paul J., 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Saint Paul Art Center, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Saint-Gaudens Memorial, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Salisbury, Harrison, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Schwabacher, W.S., 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Seven Gables Bookshop, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Sharrer, Honore, 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Sheeler, Charles, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Shubert, Katherine, 1960-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Shulman, Marshall, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Sims, Patterson, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Soby, James T., 1940-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - "South of Scranton", 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 67)
    Includes letters of congratulations for winning Carnegie Prize
  - Sotheby Parke Bernet, Inc., 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Southern Illinois University, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Soyer, Moses, 1968-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Soyer, Raphael, 1967-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Spock, Jane, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Stearn, Jimmy and Tonia, 1960-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Stephan, David, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Stuyvesant, Felicia, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Styron, William, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Sweeny, James J., 1946-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - S, circa 1960-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Tallix, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Tate, Allen, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Taubes Copal, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Thurber, Helen, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Time Magazine, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Trapp, Frank A., 1969-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Tuchmen, Barbara, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Tworkov, Jack, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - T, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - University of Nebraska, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - University of Vermont, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - University Prints, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - United States Army, 1942-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Vassar College, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - The Visionary Company, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Visual Artists and Galleries Associations, Inc., 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Vogue, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Volo, Sharon, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - V, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 97)